# IBROKHIM SHOKIROV

Ankara/TURKEY 🏫

+905534880543 📞

Ibrokhim.shokirov@gmail.com ✓

linkedin.com/in/ibrokhim-shokirov in



## **OBJECTIVE**

As long as I remember myself I wanted to become a successful Computer Engineer working for some big successful company someday. I started working on my dream when I went to high school. I started programming there and after 2 years of practice I started participating in some national and international olympiads in informatics.

After high school when I got to university I had a project from one of my professors. The reason behind this project was for me to learn steganography and also pour one of the most famous steganography algorithms "LSB Steganography" into codes which I was able to do using C#. Later while still at university I participated in 2 ethical hacking competitions. The reason behind these participations were that after my steganography application I was interested in data security which lead me to Cybe Security. That is how I got interested in security issues that applications could encounter and ways for solving them. This competitions helped me to get an internship at BEAM Teknoloji.

As my thesis (final project) at university I created a fully functional search engine which used its own web crawler. This project was actually to applications the crawler and the interface. The crawler was a console application and gethered all the informations about websites around the world and saved them inside database. For more accurate results crawler was using RAKE (Rapid Automatic Keyword Extraction) algorithm to extract keywords from page texts. Of course not all the words in a webpage is a keyword so RAKE algorithm would rate each possible keyword and after that select top 10 candidates as keywords for the webpage. The interface on the other hand was an MVC .Net web application that could go throught all the data that crawler collected and show you the best possible results for your search. This project was called Araturka for it being a national search engine for Turkey.

Also I want to mention that my education is not over until I get PhD in Computer Engineering. Of course I have still a long way to achieve my dream but I am sure that it is not far away from where I stand today.



## **EDUCATION**

#### High School | Lyceum for Gifted Students in Dushanbe

2008 - 2013

GPA: 5.0/5

My high school life was full of social and educational activities. Some of my achievements from these activities are listed in the achievement section below.

# Bachelor's Degree | Computer Engineering at Gazi University

**2014 – 2018** GPA: 2.85/4

My university life had little less social activities so I had more time to develop myself.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Web Developer | İm Park Eğitim Bilişim Ltd. Şti

#### JANUARY 2016 - MAY 2016

Started as an intern and later was offered a part-time job. I was one of the developers of the educational web project that aimed to teach foreigners Turkish language. I was programming with C# using MVC framework. I only left this job because I needed to focus on my education.

# Java Developer | PTT Genel Müdürlüğü

#### **SUMMER 2016**

I did an internship at PTT's Project Management Department as a Java Developer. Here I created a desktop application which was able to manage all the projects that company had. The application was based on basic management applications.

# **Web Security Analyst and Secure Developer | BEAM Teknoloji A. Ş.** 2017 – 2018

Started as an intern and later was offered a part-time job. Had vocation for about 3 months because of my thesis. Last 5 months I was working full-time. I was responsible for development and maintenance of the phishing project that company owned. As a secure developer I had to consider security issues that the application could go through and fix them before the deployment of the application and also add features to the existing application. As a Web Security Analyst I have had 3 projects to test for security vulnerabilities and report them with solutions. These projects belonged to some of the biggest companies in Turkey.



### **SKILLS**

- Front-End Developer
- Back-End Developer
- Secure Developer
- Web Security Analyst
- Static Code Security Analyst
- Programming
- C/C++ Developer
- Java Developer

- C# Developer
- PHP Developer
- NodeJS Developer
- MVC .NET Developer
- Cryptography and Steganography
- DBMS (MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle etc.)
- Fast Learning
- etc.

**Note:** You can find more about my skills on my LinkedIn page.



#### **LANGUAGES**

Tajik Native
Persian/Farsi Advanced
English Advanced
Turkish Advanced
Russian Intermediate
Arabic Intermediate



- Played for high school's volleyball team in 8<sup>th</sup> grade and won the regional volleyball competition for high schools.
- Played for 2 years for high school's basketball team and our team won 2<sup>nd</sup> place for the first year and 1<sup>st</sup> place the year after it.
- Participated in 7 national and international programming competitions while in high school and won 2 gold, 2 silver and 3 bronze medals.
- Studied steganography and built an application using LSB Steganography algorithm.
- Participated 2 times at STM's Capture the Flag competition which was for cyber security companies and also students. Which I was placed 12<sup>th</sup> for the first year and 15<sup>th</sup> for the second year even though I did much better second time.
- I was head of Cyber Security group at university.